## Mihir Kavatkar

mkavatkar157@gmail.com \* (508)-542-8521

#### **Career Profile**

**Full Stack Software Developer** with over 3 years of experience in delivering end-to-end applications. Core competencies include backend development in Python-Django, front-end development in React and AngularJS, relational databases, design RESTful API, design application architecture.

### **Career Highlights**

Core team member in the development of APT Webstudy (<a href="http://www.aptwebstudy.org/">http://www.aptwebstudy.org/</a>) with responsibilities of designing and implementing Restful API and using React/AngularJS for front-end implementation.

### **Professional Experience**

University of Southern California (Alzheimer's Therapeutic Research Institute)
Programmer Analyst II

San Diego, CA

August 2016 - Present

- Developed applications on Electronic Data Capture system for Alzheimer's clinical research trials.
- Developed RESTful services using Django and worked with GraphQL and Apollo GraphQL Library.
- Experience in designing web apps using Bootstrap and built using React and AngularJS.
- Proficient in AWS services like VPC, EC2, S3, Lambda, RDS, IAM, SES, Step Functions.
- Used AWS Beanstalk for deploying and scaling full-stack web applications.
- Extensive experience in unit, functional and behavior-driven testing.
- Used Continuous Delivery/Continuous Integration (CD/CI) tools Jenkins, Travis, and Git for version control of code for development.

#### Electra Vehicles, Inc. Software Developer Intern

Boston, MA

July 2016 - August 2016

- Developed application that can monitor usage of hybrid energy storage of electric or hybrid vehicles.
- Adopted a hybrid approach of using Ionic framework for cross-platform compatibility.
- Developed using JavaScript based technologies, MEAN Stack (Mongo, Express, Angular, Node).
- Experience in Angular Mocks, Mocha and Chai for basic unit testing of the application.

# Patterns and Predictions, Inc. Summer Research Assistant Intern

North Dartmouth, MA June 2015 – July 2015

- Deep learning project: A deep reinforcement learning agent that play Atari game.
- Understanding the basics of Neural Networks(NN), CNN and their implementation in Theano Library.
- Developed a script to remotely execute different instances of the project on Amazon Elastic Cloud with different hyperparameters to analyze the best performing node in the cluster. (Python, C)

# **University of Massachusetts Dartmouth Research Assistant**

North Dartmouth, MA

December 2014 – May 2016

- Master's Thesis: Projects in GPU Computing with Performance and Benchmark Analysis.
- Benchmark parallel computing language, OpenACC in terms of performance, portability, and ease-ofuse
- Two heavy computation models in the field of black hole physics a Teukolsky equation and a Scalar Collapse code was used for the research.

#### **Education**

**University of Massachusetts Dartmouth**, MA. **MS** in Computer & Information Science – 3.63 **Vidyalankar Institute of Technology**, India. **BE** in Computer Engineering – 3.5

#### Skills